this is a verse from the Terra Cotta
it's I think it's sixteen point five
verses up to sixteen yeah
having seen sites record recollected
miss recollected this is forgotten when
attending to the sign of the beloved he
experiences an impassioned mind and he
keeps on holding for him with the
arising of sites various feelings
increase for him the mind is spoiled by
designer and irritation accumulating
suffering in this way Nibbana is said to
be far away then it goes on having heard
his sound smell the smell tasted a taste
touch touch
and having known a phenomenal
recollected miss is forgotten when
attending to the sign
this is your translation so how would
you what do you think having seen sites
well first of all would you think this
applies to destruction
yes I was thinking it might apply to
know who's not practicing that's why for
him de Bona is far away but he still can
get Madonna to do it right now
for Patricia and Ivana it's invisible
even not even far away it's just not
there alexis is forgotten yeah this is
for the right sort is yeah so and how
about you when he says various feelings
increase increasing what increasing
oppression yeah and how is the pressure
felt can you feel the pressure of the
feeling in the past so increasing in the
in the presence feelings increase in the
presence yeah it's not like some it is
pressure you're always pressure by
feeling but I think it's you more
accurate to say that the increase in the
presence in how much they are present
for you because people tend to already
interpret feelings as kind of energies
and sensations and then saying them
increase means mean safety energetic all
of your feeling might be increasing or
something which is kind of true but
really they're increasing your presence
how much of that presence is over and
the more you give in the more it becomes
could you think of it attempt the arrow
second all right well no no because this
is for Inari
he doesn't get the second arrows no it's
literally like feelings will increase
when you attend to them wrongly as if
they would be more more of they have
more of their presence in that pulling
wrong manner because again we have
scratching your edge if you're not
scratching it the edge will start to
fade you start scratching it it starts
to itch more it's increasing in presence
of the edge that's it there's nothing
like future repercussions of you're
wrong attending now an accumulation of
its no it's literally you're doing it
wrongly you're gonna feel it more that's
it the feelings are more of an issue
exact more pressing more pressuring
you're more of a burdened yeah because
you're scratching them and that's making
things worse you stop scratching you're
gonna get better but this would these
will say exactly that by Bromley
attending to it they increase wrongly
returning to the losing the context
losing perspective on account of the
scene losing perspective on account of
the hurt so one looks at the attractive
well it happens before you look
attractive the attractive comes within your range
the attractive comes within your range
you've already picked the sign of the
attractive and then you choose to look
like you wouldn't you cannot look at the
attractive accidentally because it's not
attractive at that time yet you can look
at accidental it's something then you
realize it was attractive and then
that's the time when you have a choice
well I look again we'll have a better
look or shall I refrain from looking and
that's what this refers to so you choose
them to attend wrong as in you choose to
look again although you know that now
you perceive it as attractive so the
context of attractiveness has a reason
in the mind and now you have target
and that's your responsibility and for
as long as you keep doing that the
context of attractiveness will remain
lingering around you could you're
maintaining it in your mind to continue
to invite me to be far away from New
Bern and so you said recollected missus
forgotten me
rather than I rather just just general
mindfulness like can we say it's
recollecting particular thing like maybe
in this case sure I see it's nothing
should put it thicker in that sense
rather than just being mindful oh yes of
course no there always has to be a
reference for a recollecting it's I mean
yeah I'm just mindful of hearing now
moment means you're mindful of anything
yeah but in this case it's see because
he's talking about the senses yes
and obviously the chief mindfulness of
mindfully to the body or the other
mindfulness of within or standing place
for the my place of the body that's kind
of the only mindfulness you can do even
mindfulness of the thoughts again he
would reveal the body being there as a
city basis so you would have to be there
yeah so there's something like it's
losing the context in regard to the seen
heard smelled taste touch and so on the
context being the body given there
beforehand as a as a container for these
things to be so there is no problem in
in things presenting themselves as
attractive or as repulsive if you see
correctly on the basis of the body you
see that on the basis of the body that's
not mine things present themselves as
attractive as repulsive as neutral which
are equally not mine because they're on
the basis of the body they cannot be in
me you forget in the basis of the body
you and attractive or you and repulsive
or you a neutral form a relationship and
even that's not necessary that is a
problem but that's a problem that you
have to basically uproot you can't just
say no to it and stop
because that's still not your doing but
once you form the relationship with with
the scene on account of its attraction
or on account of its repulsion is like
or I hate that that's when you when you
choose them to act out of that
relationship that's that's how you
perpetuate the problem and fuel it and
make the feelings increase as a result
of it so next time the pressure
relationship will be even even heavier
it's harder to be yes yeah exactly it's
harder to be so feeling feelings become
harder to bear yeah as opposed because
you can give in today if you didn't they
wouldn't they will be less and less and
less hard to so they would sit in yeah
and that's what it said he wouldn't feel
anything you wouldn't feel feeling he's
the burden
there's no like some feelings a burden
no feeling in his nature is a burden
feeling towards attractive feeling that
was repulsive feeling those neutral it's
a burden either way because you are
subjected to it because it's upon you see
well it's that which is not 42 Gina you
cannot possibly compare the aggregate to
feeling for another hand and the
petitioner from an impersonal standpoint
you're either closer to one or the other
so the aggregator feeling for another
hand is the same good it is for
petitioner something out there that's
not felt nor carry beyond
however petitioner is pressured by that
thing out there which cannot be felt not
owned and because of the pressure he
feels in his on he owns it so the
aggregate of feeling for another hunt is
what if a grieving feeling is it's not
the aggregate of you touching that is
the actual aggregate of feeling it's a
mistake in regard to the aggregates and
she stated petitioner so it's not that
you like in practice you have to start
from two to two another hunt but if you
want to look via reticle in the
structure it's the structure of the
other hand segregates that's what's
first that's always been that that's how
good I said who put on his knob in the
aggregates cannot take their realness
you know part of them it's not away from
them either it's desire and lost in
regards to the aggregates including a
great feeling that these aggregates you
put on is there did your assumption your
attachment is their house thing is that
so really you should ask what is the
aggregate of feeling for regional
clarify that and you have the aggregate
of another hand not like hmm let me get
to the theoretical point of aggregate
for another hunt because you'll be
arriving at it through being subjected
to the pressure of the pressure of the
feeling that you already are which means
you won't be arriving at it correctly
he's said to talk about two different
types of aggregates that's actually what
the brother does he says yes yes the
there's the Condors
and there's the Platonic idea Batman but
I don't I don't do that without
qualifying it right because it's already
misunderstood enough because many people
would think oh dude you know I read the
suta and pretend soon our hunt and I get
the idea of it and then idea stands for
that which other days as in a Zappa to
dinner I understand what the other hand
is and now I just have to adhere to my
method or technique or practice and our
magical arrive at it no you cannot
understand what it is which is why
you're still petitioner understanding
whether nowadays you cannot be able to
just have feelings now and then if you
lose does does that feeling disappear
it's a wrong question because it's you
don't lose the assumption in regard to
the feeling your assumption is your
feeling there is no feeling left or
right from it so you trying to separate
is impossible the only way to separate
your assumption from your feeling is to
become another hand so asking them what
happens to feeling with my assumption
ceases you cannot conceive for as long
as your assumptions till then
because your feeling is your assumption
your aggregates are your assumption
that's a bit taken up wrongly
but those are the only ones you know so
the same question would be wrong to ask
for any again what happens to
consciousness when there is no oppa Dona
Europa an easier consciousness Europa
Don is Pancho pod anaconda sources
feelings sees you say poop analyses
so who to Gina's feeling which is
feeling of conveyed and oppa Donna it's
completely doesn't exist in Harlan he
had ceased everything the five don't you
put on a condom six for another so it's
important to realize that the only way
to understand and what's left is to
become an ardent doctor theoretically
compare punch open an account with punch
akanda and then get the idea I mean you
can get the idea theoretical but don't
confuse it as understanding it for what
it is can see you can result in that
kind of subtle but yet quite profound
and fundamental separation ah Madonna
and my assumption waiting and my
assumption in regard to my Veda I know
you paid enough easier okay Donna you're
angry it's our Europa Donna the
container for petitioner is opener of
everything so you can measure you well
you can measure the amount of you put on
in regard to how much you're liable to
suffer slippery feelings of if you
oppression by sure that means the amount
of pressure
yes yeah so not being pressured at all
no being pressured up which you could
also say it's not feeling it's not fair
exactly
so tell me the feeling you feel is the
feeling of Fupa Donna so how could you
be a feeling without being felt you
become an out of hunt
that's how so hurry yourself because
says it's especially another Eric Harris
I when enabled assigned for practices he
exhausted feeling he doesn't have
cumulate feeling exhausted humilate
means he doesn't mean a increase through
scratching carelessly it will each more
so he's not accumulating that he stopped
scratching stops itching heals and then
he does not hit you know there is
nothing felt anymore so we did
so he he is not impassioned by science
having seen a scientist he is
recollected having seen the site the
complex remains in pattern so he does
not lose the sight of the body being the
container of whatever seen pleasant
unpleasant neutral doesn't matter so he
doesn't forsake that image for going
towards the the pleasant sight which is
what definition of passion is he
experiences a de passionate yes passion
of mind and he doesn't keep on holding
because it's impossible to hold in the
first place and he does not forget that
for one seeing a sight like this while I
was a practicing feeling he's exhausted
not accumulate this presence or the
feeling fades away does not increase it
fades away completely you could say it's
a ceased and cannot arise this is
diminishing suffering in this way new
bond is it to be
so he did miniatures he's liability to
suffering so he's doing an Aryan is
doing this but just keeping that
recollection and restrain things yes
things they're sort of trying to induce
the scratch all he needs to do is
restraint because the restraint for me
for him would mean maintenance of the
right context that he has obtained by
becoming a sort of owner that's why for
petition you need a bit more than to
just appear you need to restrain is a
necessary basis but you also need to
then understand what the right context
is otherwise you can restrain as much as
you want but you still remain holding
onto the ground context not realizing
the relationship that whatever scene is
within the necessary basis of the body
that you are mindful of and including
your own sense of self is within the
necessary basis of the body did you
mindful oh so there is no external to
the necessary basis of the body that you
are reflecting correctly fully dwell on
that is a particular there is no
external once you go through the few
times of anxiety and fear that you will
drown and it will kill you you get used
to it you stop resisting it and then you
find it liberating how much it will
bother you that depends how good your
ceiling is established how much pressure
you carry anyway how many habits of
scratching and carrying you have to
restrain so it doesn't need to always be
unpleasant but I think more often than
not today I think it's going to be more
unpleasant than not it's more more often
than not people are much more into the
senses than they used to be that's the
decline the threshold of your being is already
the threshold of your being is already
far far proliferated because you know
even in that there's a space speaking
earlier like even you know even the
underprivileged in the Western societies
that in a privileged
you don't go hungry or something you
might not be able to get fashionable
things and some kind of items of
entertainment and whatnot but far from
that you are actually starving it or not
being able to eat on the contrary my
most people are weight problem certainly
in Western Europe so it just tells you
like we're we're the starting point is
but back in the day even the efferent
people would still worry about you know
next month the king might come and kill
all of my family members and take all of
my possessions and you leave that with
the back of your mind and you just have
to accept it and every day has that
perspective on it oh yeah my little mud
hut with my six children in a slightest
earthquake the thing might fall and kill
us all at night and you you get used to
it so you don't necessarily feel the
that kind of intense surgeons show it
but doesn't mean it's not there then you
live under it and today people don't
what's there you might worry about
somebody say something that upsets you
it essentially shakes you but it's far
from any actual threat
because that's the words that's the
starting point which means that needs to
be undone and that to me like in present
day if somebody's trying to do that it's
going to be unpleasant initially because
you're far out there in the senses
depending on constant activity constant
engagement constant distraction constant
input input constant everything because
the same in the same fashion
the more you scratch the more it will
itch so you got used to the point of
scratching at the click of a button tap
on a phone phone call company food food
food eat five six times a day now that
becomes normal necessity so if you can't
sustain that level of engagement you're
gonna be suffer on account of it and if
you don't go through that suffering of
that withdrawal well you'll never arrive
at this position whereby you can
maintain the perspective and then see
your choice in choosing to go that way
or choosing not to go that way that's
invisible for most people that's what
they saw
you know like central design is just
nature it's just natural I think it has
nothing to do with me the fact that you
can say no to it means it has everything
to do with you whatever you can say no
to you responsible for
so revise that and see what are the
things I can say no to so you can't say
no to breathing to your heart beating to
aging to getting sick you can't say in
order to die you can't say no so that's
not on you you can't say no to hunger
sure you can literally has no center of
everything else which means you're
responsible for choosing to do it you
know as simple as that
so then don't choose based on desire
don't choose based on your world and
don't choose based on desire to distract
yourself need to distract yourself and
then you getting ready to practice it
down
that which you can say no that's what
you're responsible
you can say no tweeting you can't say no
to needing food but you can say no to
leaning certain type of food like when
you have a choice you can say no to
choosing on account of taste you can
always say no to sexual intercourse
that's why I understand it's ok it's not
to be done
he must be abandoned you can say no to
acting out of anger doesn't matter how
angry you get how upset you are you
choose to have target which means you
can say no to it ok say no to know why
you can say no to IT not feeling which
is how feeling gets maintained enough
and how feeling increases in its
presence so indirectly you can say no to
all of the five aggregates which is
whether or not it is generally people
who think that would be some kind of
repression yeah that's a say indirectly
you can't oppress things indeed if you
say no to this the results in something
else that you want to resolve the
question is when you were like no no no
but yeah sometimes you need to repress
yourself yeah you need to suppress you
need to scratch like a mania if you if
your arms are itching you have to stop
scratching in order for them to heal so
here by all means repressed yourself
what is that so look and even through
the point of view it's regression so you
get angry in one instance then you act
out of it and then the results of that
in harm and whatever else you can cause
further anger the other example gets
angry and then it oppresses it so which
is better overall both are affected by
anger in the first place so whether you
refresh yourself or not makes no
difference yet the one who is repressed
has not caused all this other load of
suffering and results and repercussions
of his actions someone say well that
person requests now they're keeping it
in store to white people if they do it's
because they haven't repressed
themselves on that occasion which means
they haven't remained true to the
principle of repression as incense
restrains us that's the the the argument
for celibacy against celibacy now you've
been in your sexual desire keep it in QT
and then you go in the list hundreds of
children yeah does it to underlay the
thing because it's built up if you if
you choose to to go ahead molest
children or do whatever else on account
of that's because you chose to not
repress yourself anymore so you cannot
say I chose to not repress myself
because of repression that's a
contradiction in terms because of
repression you would have stayed
repressed as in you will be practicing
censors trained correctly so you're just
weak you just could not see through
that's the reason your choice so same
somebody who who abstains from
scratching the rich and when they give
in they're gonna scratch twice as hard
there's nothing to do with their
abstaining let's do be their own
weakness in regard to the abstaining to
their own like a loss of perspective in
regard to the abstaining
because if they have a lose have a lost
perspective of realizing that the itch
will disappear altogether if they see
through the their non abstaining from
scratching if they haven't lost that
sight they would have given in so if you
want to say the direct reason for
molesting or doing
stuff on account of your depression it's
you losing perspective when I come to be
repression not the repression again it's
always on you doesn't matter how much
pressure it's on you to do it
if you can say no to it you will be
responsible for doing it because it's
the you get you angry I mean the person
goes goes away that continues to brood
so it's not doing okay so why like you
see if that anger is happy that the
anger keeps growing what was the first
point of anger your repression or before
your depression where did I anger
originate before so why do you blame my
passion for your anger Brewin can anger
brew if it hasn't a reason in the first
place no can you repress anger if it hasn't
no can you repress anger if it hasn't
arisen in the first place No
so your anger brewing is not a result of
your depression your anchor brewing is a
result of your anger so the same thing
is there yeah
hey thank you just you did repression
which is a good thing
yeah prevented you from from like
spilling it out there and affecting
further domains as opposed to just your
mind you affected your verbal expression
you effective physical if you don't you
still cultivating this it's the same
anyway they're doing before but now you
at least you have a chance of seeing it
once you depress your physical output in
verbal output of acting out of anger you
have a chance to see that aha
so it's still in my mind that same anger
did I have restraint are you blaming
restraint for brewing means complete
loss with perspective and seeing failing
to see that it brews cuz he was already
there before which is why I practiced
restraint in the first place there's
nothing to restrain anger doesn't right
then there's the press
and then there is my overview where it's
still in me
now I must still get out another way I
might as well go getting to kickbox
because that's their the healthy way to
get up and yeah well I think there is
the infinite amount of magical
connection that people can make you want
to try avoid the responsibility for your
reason state of mind so when it's King
kickboxing or finger-painting or slam
poetry it's your magical belief that
connects this is the out outlet of my
anger normal sexual desire so say you
responsible for T for whatever you
choose to do an account of it yeah
finger-painting is better than harming
somebody physically but you're still
giving in to to the need of acting out
of anger which means you're still
affected by the anger which means you
not gonna uproot it so yes but it is
absolutely necessary that wrong will be
abandoned then these verses where that can can
then these verses where that can can
start to apply then you realize the
responsibilities on you never leaves you
and if you choose to go this direction
feeling will increase in its pressure
and presence and burden if you choose to
not go that direction feeling will
decrease in this pressure presence
Umberto eCos Unabomber which is what the
banner will be so measurements
oh yeah sure then I ain't close to sure
yeah practicing well but feelings are
increasing in that sense there's no
increasing yeah it's just a favor just a
pleasant feeling there's increase but
it's saying when feelings I exhausted
yeah nothing spell evening great and
it's a problem you're far away from me
but it's it's well it's it's bigger
problem than suffering as the suitor
says he regards pain as as a dart yes
and pleasure is a deadly arrow pain pain
pleasure is pleasure and pain is it then
there yeah so this so pain is even worse
always the pain pain but pleasure it's
like the pain so you need to regard that
also as a dangerous and deadly in the
same sense so nothing is felt so the
measure of your progress is the measure
of the extent how much you're not liable
to feelings at all and they says they
describe how much less you feel on the
garbageman's describes that nothing being yeah that's
describes that nothing being yeah that's
Pleasant in some regard so that's a
different kind of well that's the type
of pleasure you can understand by not
feeling anything
not by to feeling this pleasure I get to
understand what pressure on feeling it
is impossible
you could when you read this he doesn't
feel anything for a puto generis cuz for
him feeling is his existence feeling is
like that's what they would freak out
when the Buddha would describe me burn
and they would understand what it is and
they saw there was killers they were
crushes they will destroy me I will not
be so again you have a choice do you
think well you can stay on the level of
existence that you've got accustomed to
are you can't complain then when things
don't go your way when other people
upset you when you lose the loved ones
when you start losing your own health
like use everything else it's on you you
chose to stay with these things apply
you chose to hold on to it by constantly
refusing to give up scratching of
revenge
that's why beings at owners of
directions choices you make they cannot
possibly like be someone else's the
result of those things so if people are
born here or reborn elsewhere or
reappear somewhere else it's it's simply
because of the choices they're making
and they continue to make so in some
these people say oh you're lucky to be a
month why for choosing to be a month yeah well
why for choosing to be a month yeah well
I'm lucky in as much I'm still alive
that's as far as the luck goes but I
chose to be like I made you have to be
safe unit a month that's on you
oh but I family as a family been thrown
upon you or have you produced it through
sexual intercourse through endogenous oh
so you're fully responsible to the
things you could have said no now you
have a burden to weight yeah sure so now
you can't because of what you chose to
do so if you cannot give up the life
that and you want to give it up
whose fault is it your own fault there
is some so you think wisely before you
act it's never too late to start practicing
it's never too late to start practicing
that principle
payment you must make if you wanna have
to you can't just get it for nothing
yeah yeah just because you well I think
the people quadrant in charge it's quite
accurate what he said
so if you give up a little I just said
that if you give up little you get a
little bit of peace if you give up a lot
you get a lot of these if you give her
everything you get the opportunities
literally it's a heavy things and peace
are mutually exclusive having things as
in internally regarding them as yours
their beloved and so on having right to
them a fully entitled to possess this
and so on so giving up the ownership of
things to that extent
so normally is a constant trying to get
away from that you just feel good but
you just playing this you exactly it's a
very it's a very clever trap that matter
sets up because see you think you're
making progress by avoiding the painful
feeling on account of pleasant feeling
but you fail to see then either way you
remain bound by the feelings and that's
what mother wants he doesn't care
whether you suffer or your present as
long as you don't say no to feelings as
long as you don't step outside of his
reach and he's the main so that's why
whether you act out the pleasant feeling
or a pleasant feeling if you keep acting
under the pressure of the feeling
whatever the feeling is means you will
you will you will suffer and you will be
bound by that so you can you can't have
any bad you wanna please